import type { ExamData } from "../../exam-data";

export const examData: ExamData = {
    title: "Fuselage, Wings and Stabilizing Surfaces",
    questions: [
        {
            "id": 1,
            "question": "What is the purpose of the wing main spar?",
            "options": [
                "To withstand bending and torsional loads",
                "To withstand compressive and torsional loads", 
                "To withstand compressive and shear loads",
                "To withstand bending and shear loads"
            ],
            "answer": 3
        },
        {
            "id": 2,
            "question": "What is the purpose of wing ribs?",
            "options": [
                "To withstand the fatigue stresses",
                "To shape the wing and support the skin",
                "To house the fuel and the landing gear",
                "To provide local support for the skin"
            ],
            "answer": 1
        },
        {
            "id": 3,
            "question": "What is the purpose of stringers?",
            "options": [
                "To absorb the torsional and compressive stresses",
                "To produce stress risers and support the fatigue metres",
                "To prevent buckling and bending by supporting and stiffening the skin",
                "To support the primary control surfaces"
            ],
            "answer": 2
        },
        {
            "id": 4,
            "question": "The airframe structure must remain substantially intact after experiencing:",
            "options": [
                "the design ultimate load times a 1.5 safety factor",
                "the design limit load plus the design ultimate load",
                "three times the safety factor",
                "the design limit load times a 1.5 factor of safety"
            ],
            "answer": 3
        },
        {
            "id": 5,
            "question": "In the construction of airframes the primary purpose of frames or formers is to:",
            "options": [
                "provide a means of attaching the stringers and skin panels",
                "oppose hoop stresses and provide shape and form to the fuselage",
                "form the entrance door posts",
                "support the wings"
            ],
            "answer": 1
        },
        {
            "id": 6,
            "question": "How can wing bending moments be reduced in flight?",
            "options": [
                "By using aileron 'up-float' and keeping the centre section fuel tanks full for as long as possible",
                "By using aileron 'up-float' and using the fuel in the wings last",
                "By having tail-mounted engines and using aileron 'down-float'",
                "By having wing-mounted engines and using the wing fuel first"
            ],
            "answer": 1
        },
        {
            "id": 7,
            "question": "Regarding a safe life structure:\n1. will only fail after a known number of operations or hours of use.\n2. should not fail until a predicted number of fatigue cycles has been achieved.\n3. has a programmed inspection cycle to detect and rectify faults.\n4. is changed before its predicted life is reached.",
            "options": [
                "1 and 2 apply",
                "1 and 3 apply",
                "2, 3 and 4 apply",
                "all of the above apply"
            ],
            "answer": 2
        },
        {
            "id": 8,
            "question": "A fail-safe structure:\n1. has a programmed inspection cycle to detect and rectify faults.\n2. is changed before its predicted life is reached.\n3. has redundant strength which will tolerate a certain amount of structural damage.\n4. is secondary structure of no structural significance.",
            "options": [
                "1 and 2 apply",
                "1 and 3 apply",
                "3 and 4 apply",
                "all of the above apply"
            ],
            "answer": 1
        },
        {
            "id": 9,
            "question": "The skin of a modern pressurized aircraft:",
            "options": [
                "is made up of light alloy steel sheets built on the monocoque principle",
                "houses the crew and the payload",
                "provides aerodynamic lift and prevents corrosion by keeping out adverse weather",
                "is primary load bearing structure carrying much of the structural loads"
            ],
            "answer": 3
        },
        {
            "id": 10,
            "question": "The primary purpose of the fuselage is to:",
            "options": [
                "support the wings",
                "house the crew and payload",
                "keep out adverse weather",
                "provide access to the cockpit"
            ],
            "answer": 1
        },
        {
            "id": 11,
            "question": "Station numbers (Stn) and water lines (WL) are:",
            "options": [
                "a means of locating airframe structure and components",
                "passenger seat locations",
                "runway markings for guiding the aircraft to the terminal",
                "compass alignment markings"
            ],
            "answer": 0
        },
        {
            "id": 12,
            "question": "Flight deck windows are constructed from:",
            "options": [
                "an amalgam of strengthened glass and vinyl with rubber pressure seals",
                "strengthened glass with shock absorbing clear vinyl interlayers and rubber pressure seals",
                "strengthened clear vinyl with an electrical conducting coat for de-icing and rubber pressure seals",
                "strengthened glass with rubber seals"
            ],
            "answer": 1
        },
        {
            "id": 13,
            "question": "A cantilever wing:",
            "options": [
                "is externally braced with either struts and/or bracing wires",
                "is supported at one end only with no external bracing",
                "has both an upper an lower aerofoil section",
                "folds at the root section to ease storage in confined spaces"
            ],
            "answer": 1
        },
        {
            "id": 14,
            "question": "A torsion box:",
            "options": [
                "is a structure within the fuselage to withstand compression, bending and twisting loads",
                "is a structure formed between the wing spars, skin and ribs to resist bending and twisting loads",
                "is a structure within the wing for housing the fuel tanks, flight controls and landing gear",
                "is a structure designed to reduce the weight"
            ],
            "answer": 1
        },
        {
            "id": 15,
            "question": "A lightening hole in a rib:",
            "options": [
                "prevents lightning strikes damaging the fuselage",
                "provides a means of passing cables and controls through a pressure bulkhead",
                "collects and disposes of electrical charges",
                "lightens and stiffens the structure"
            ],
            "answer": 3
        },
        {
            "id": 16,
            "question": "Control surface flutter:",
            "options": [
                "provides additional lift for take-off and landing in the event of engine failure",
                "occurs at high angles of attack",
                "is a destructive vibration that must be damped out within the flight envelope",
                "is a means of predicting the critical safe life of the wing"
            ],
            "answer": 2
        },
        {
            "id": 17,
            "question": "Control surface flutter is minimized by:",
            "options": [
                "reducing the moment of the critical engine",
                "aerodynamic balance of the control cables",
                "changing the wings before they reach their critical life",
                "mass balance of the control surface"
            ],
            "answer": 3
        },
        {
            "id": 18,
            "question": "A damage tolerant structure:",
            "options": [
                "has degree of structural strength redundancy spread over a large area",
                "is light, non load bearing structure, damage to which will not adversely affect the aircraft",
                "is replaced when it reaches its predicted life",
                "need not be repaired until the aircraft undergoes deep maintenance"
            ],
            "answer": 0
        },
        {
            "id": 19,
            "question": "Aircraft structures consists mainly of:",
            "options": [
                "light alloy steel sheets with copper rivets and titanium or steel materials at points requiring high strength",
                "magnesium alloy sheets with aluminium rivets and titanium or steel at points requiring high strength",
                "aluminium alloy sheets and rivets with titanium or steel materials at points requiring high strength",
                "aluminium sheets and rivets with titanium or steel materials at points requiring high strength"
            ],
            "answer": 2
        },
        {
            "id": 20,
            "question": "The Maximum Zero Fuel Mass (MZFM) of an aircraft is:",
            "options": [
                "the maximum permissible take-off mass of the aircraft",
                "the maximum permissible mass of an aircraft with no usable fuel",
                "the maximum permissible mass of an aircraft with zero payload",
                "the maximum permissible landing mass"
            ],
            "answer": 1
        }
    ]
}